

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

20, Building 6A, Rahul Nagar, Kothrud Pune, Maharashtra, India

□ (+91) 9970677761 | **□** pise.mandar@gmail.com | **□** mandarpise24 | **⑤** pise.mandar

# Summary\_

Current Senior Software Developer for CAE Pre-Processor Generator4 at GNS Engineering. 7+ years experience in developing CAD, CAE and PLM Products. Specializing in application development using C++, OOPS and STL. Comfortable on both Windows and Linux as development platform. Likes to automate time wasting tasks. Interested in learning new technologies and tools.

# Work Experience\_\_\_\_\_

### **GNS Engineering India Pvt.Ltd.**

Pune, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (LEAD)

March 2019 - Till Date

- Responsible for development of Preprocessing CAE Product Generator4 using C++ and QT.
- Provide solutions to local Generator4 users in India office.
- Work closely with Product managers from Germany and Australia.
- · Manage Software Development Team in India.

### Altair Engineering India Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2015 - March 2019

- Implemented a Reader and Writer Interface for Medina .bif and .bof file format in Hyperworks Desktop Application. This project helped customers to use their legacy data (Generated in Medina) in Hyperworks.
- Responsible for Development and Enhancement of Hyper-View result readers.
- Responsible for supporting various solver binary output files. Predominantly Worked on LS-Dyna (D3plot), Radioss (A00), Nastran (Op2, XDB, HDF5) and Pamcrash(ERFH5).
- Resolve customer critical issues related to the result readers.
- Mentor and Train Junior Team Members.

#### 3DPLM Software Solutions Ltd.

Mumbai, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

June 2012 - May 2015

- Part of CAD Integration Development team for "Enovia SmarTeam" (Dassault Systems product comes under ENOVIA brand).
- Quick analysis and resolution of the high priority as well as complex customer issues.
- Identify and make use of various Microsoft Office and CAD APIs to provide new as well as useful functionalities in the product.
- Working collaboratively with cross functional teams.
- Developed batch scripts to automate source code management related activities.

# Education

### **Defense Institute of Advanced Technology**

Pune, India

July 2010 - May 2012

MASTER OF TECHNOLOGY IN MODELLING AND SIMULATION (DISTINCTION)

• Got a MHRD Scholarship (Monthly Stipend) which is given to GATE (Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering) Qualified Students.

• Successfully completed project on "Projectile penetration using Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics" as Master's Thesis under guidance of Dr. Smita D. Naik (Scientist 'F', Defence Research Development Organization). The thesis dealt with the modelling of projectile penetration problem using Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics and Study the effect of most sensitive parameters involved.

## Fr. Cancecao Rodrigues Institute of Technology

Navi Mumbai, India

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (FIRST CLASS)

July 2006 - June 2010

November 15, 2019 Mandar Pise · Resume 1